United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records WAG.172
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records
1945-1993
1970-1993
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local #2 (Manhattan)
WAG.172
39.25 Linear Feet in 39 record cartons and 1 folder in a shared box.
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 represented workers in the plumbing industry in Manhattan and the Bronx from the late 19th century until the late 1990s. This collection contains documents and photographs relating to the union's activities from the mid-1940s through early 1990s. The bulk of the collection is from after 1970. Materials include legal briefs, correspondence, administrative files, education materials, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Content Note
The United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records contain documents and photographs relating to the union's activities from the mid-1940s through early 1990s. The bulk of the collection is from after 1970. Materials include legal briefs, correspondence, administrative files, education materials, and photographs.
Related Archival Materials
Materials related to the government investigation and trial of the officials of Local 2 can be found in Series IV of the James McNamara Papers (WAG 129).
Historical/Biographical Note
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 represented workers in the plumbing industry in Manhattan and the Bronx from the late 19th century until the late 1990s. The local was plagued by corruption, and in 1993, the national appointed a trustee to run the local. In 1997, Local 2 was dissolved and its members placed into the jurisdiction of Local 1.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 1, 2001. The accession numbers 2002.025 and 2002.026 are associated with this gift.
Briefs (legal documents); Legal documents.; Correspondence.; Legal files.; Photographs.; Labor unions -- New York (State); Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local #2 (Manhattan); United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local #2 (Manhattan)
- Framed photos, undated (Box 1)
- Framed photos, undated (Box 2)
- Framed photos, undated (Box 3)
- Minutes of Constitution Committee, 1971 (Box 4)
- Real Estate Records, 1971 (Box 4)
- Training Tests, undated (Box 4)
- Written Tests, undated (Box 4)
- Tax Returns, 1992 (Box 4)
- Mike Celletti Correspondence, 1992 (Box 4)
- Baseball League Correspondence, undated (Box 4)
- General Files (Administration and Education), 1990s (Box 5)
- General Files (Administration and Education), 1990s (Box 6)
- General Files (Legal Briefs), 1985 (Box 6)
- Arbitrations, undated (Box 6)
- Legal Briefs- Open Files, 1980s (Box 7)
- General Correspondence, 1980s (Box 7)
- Pension Fund Correspondence, 1980s (Box 8)
- National Labor Relations Board cases, 1980s-1990 (Box 9)
- Legal Briefs, 1988-1991 (Box 10)
- Legal Briefs, 1990s (Box 11)
- Legal Briefs, 1990s (Box 12)
- Correspondence and Briefs (by contractor), undated (Box 12)
- Correspondence and Briefs (by contractor), 1980s-1990s (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 14)
- Negotiations, 1991 (Box 15)
- Contractor Correspondence and General Files, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
- General Files, 1980s (Box 16)
- Correspondence, 1980s (Box 17)
- General Files, 1980-1992 (Box 18)
- Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 20)
- Petty Cash Book, 1945 (Box 20)
- Minutes, 1969-1980s (Box 21)
- Contracts, 1970-1988 (Box 21)
- Correspondence and Legal Briefs, 1988-1991 (Box 21)
- Reciprocal Agreements, 1980s-1990s (Box 21)
- General Files, 1980s-1990s (Box 22)
- Legal Briefs, 1991 (Box 23)
- General Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 24)
- General Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 25)
- Death Records (alphabetical), 1989 (Box 26)
- Death Records, 1989 (Box 27)
- Death Records, 1984 (Box 28)
- Correspondence - Local 2 Constitutions, 1985-1992 (Box 29)
- Test Papers (Apprentices), 1970 (Box 29)
- Weekly Job Reports, 1988 (Box 30)
- Contracts, 1973 (Box 30)
- Policy Paper on Minimum Wage (Frank Barbaro), undated (Box 30)
- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 31)
- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 33)
- Legal Correspondence, 1990 (Box 34)
- Legal Correspondence, 1990 (Box 35)
- Negotiating Committee Reports, 1979 (Box 36)
- Executive Board Minutes, 1978-1981 (Box 36)
- Souvenir Programs, 1970-1980 (Box 36)
- Apprenticeship Questions, undated (Box 37)
- Photographs, undated (Box 37)
- Death Records, undated (Box 37)
- Legal Correspondence, 1990 (Box 38)
- Death Records, 1993 (Box 39)
- Annual Enterainment and Ball Committee Group Portraits, 1954-1961 (Box OS001, Folder 1)